some people. It's uh Wednesday, August
20th. Thanks for joining us. We're here
here on Drogram. I'm Ted R. That's John
Kuryaku. Monday through Friday, 5:00 PM
Eastern time. Um John, you said it's a
bit of a slow news day. And I think
that's kind of true because we're kind
of in between a lot of things that are
sort of uh in the middle of happening.
But it doesn't mean that we have nothing
to talk about. So,
>> no, that's right. There's Hey, listen.
So long as you read the New York Post
every day, there's plenty to talk about.
always read the New York Post. So, in no
particular order because that's not how
we do things here. Uh, and by the way,
uh, please feel free to chime in with
your uh, your questions inside the
Rumble or the YouTube chat if you're
joining us live. If you're listening to
us later on, thank you so much for
joining us and do consider joining us
live if you ever have the chance. All
right, so New York Times has a piece
today about the it's a deep dive about
uh, voter registration. Democrats are
getting clobbered on voter registration.
um they've lost and half million voters
to the Republicans in just 30 out of 50
states between 20 and 2024. So, we'll
talk about that and what it means for
the Democratic party. Um Fox News hosts,
not surprisingly, they tend to be in the
tank for Donald Trump, although there
was once a time, remember, when the
order went out like not to do that, but
they they changed their mind. Anyway, um
there's a lawsuit, a lot of def a lot of
discovery that turned private
information into public records. Now, we
know that people like Janine Piro, we
have their internal communications with
people like Sean Hannity, uh and they're
squabbbling and super super interesting.
We'll get into sort of some inside Fox
News dish and uh you know, let's see if
they should even be pretending to be
objective reporters. Oklahoma.
>> Yeah.
now wants to is has is subjecting
teachers only from New York and
California to a test to determine
whether they're too woke to teachers in
Oklahoma or not. Uh Israel literally
just um within the last hour reinvaded
Gaza. That was anticipated. We'll get
into that. They're currently fighting in
Kunis and in Gaza City. Um, and Israel
has officially declared effectively the
death of the two-state solution, uh, at
least in the West Bank. That kind of
makes it the whole thing. That E1
project that we talked about the other
day, has now been formally approved, and
we'll we'll get into all that. Um,
there's a few other things going on. The
redistricting battles are still
happening, and of course, we're looking
to see if any progress is going to be
made uh on the peace negotiations
between Russia and Ukraine. John, what
would you like to do first?
>> Well, you know what? Let's start with
the Middle East just because it's so
near and dear to my heart. I had I had a
really lovely um coffee meeting this
morning with a young intern from the
Jordanian embassy. He watches the show.
He reached out on LinkedIn. I can never
say no to a cup of coffee. So, we we got
together today and it was a it was a
really delightful conversation. Um, but
one of the things that that he reminded
me of that I actually had I guess pushed
back into the sort of the recesses of my
of my brain is that many Palestinians,
especially Palestinians in the diaspora,
especially in the Middle Eastern
diaspora,
don't like each other. Right? It's
partly a generational thing. It's in
some cases a uh a religious thing
because you know it used to be that 10%
of the Palestinians in Palestine were
Christian like 8020 Orthodox and
Catholic. Um most of the Palestinian
Christians have have immigrated to the
West and most of them to the United
States or Australia
and it's left a lot of very angry
refugees in the in the in the region.
50% of the population of Jordan is
Palestinian, but but they're divided by
generation.
They're divided by whether they are the
descendants of Palestinian refugees from
1948 from the Nakba or if they're recent
arrivals.
>> There are some Palestinians who moved to
the Persian Gulf and worked for 30 years
and made tons of money and then have
gone back and now all of a sudden
they're doing better than most
Jordanians are doing.
So he said in the west, especially in
the United States, one of the things
that he's noticed is that even those of
us or especially those of us who are pro
Palestinian, we have this this idea that
Palestinians are monolithic and they're
not. And they're not.
>> That's super interesting.
>> Yeah. And that's why
>> that's true. Yeah,
>> the the reason the way we got on to that
conversation was we were talking about
the one-state solution versus the
two-state solution. And I said, you
know, there there already is one state.
How's that working out for everybody?
Not very well. You can't really have a
two-state solution because you've got
Mahmud Abbas who's like I always say 19
years into a four-year term and suddenly
finds himself to be a billionaire
despite the fact that his people are
among the poorest in the world.
>> He's just a good investor.
>> Yeah. Apparently just like Marjorie
Taylor Green.
>> That's right. Good speculator. And then,
you know, you've got the three-state
solution, which nobody wants to talk
about because there's really no
connection between East Bank uh sorry,
East Bank, West Bank Palestinians and
and Gaza Palestinians.
So, what's the solution? Even the
Palestinians don't have a proposed
solution. And now today, we've got the
Israelis reinvading Gaza City. Why? just
so they can kill the people who managed
to escape last time and blow up the
tunnels that uh that the Israelis were
responsible for digging in the first
place.
>> Now, John, I have to say uh you know,
the shadow of all of this reinvasion is
of course uh the ceasefire deal, right?
So, there's a current ceasefire deal on
the table. Hamas has already officially
signed off all the remaining hostages,
the 20 uh the 20 live ones and the 30
corpses would be released. Um and this
would be a 60-day ceasefire and the
deadline for it is on Friday. I mean,
this is Israel's answer, right?
Basically, no ceasefire.
>> Yeah. No ceasefire.
No way. Remember,
>> they don't care about the hostages. They
don't care.
>> They don't care. They don't care. And
they made it clear from from the very
beginning that they don't care. And like
we always said,
there's a benefit to Benjamin Netanyahu
for this thing to go on forever because
so long as the the war continues and
Netanyahu remains prime minister, he's
not going to be prosecuted for for
corruption,
right? So why
>> Thank you so much for Thank you so much
uh Hey Mike, for the very generous $100
donation. Oh, thank you. Thank you. Hey,
Mike. Thank you so much.
Yeah.
And tomorrow I'm going to be on with
Eric. Who's Eric?
>> Who's
probably
>> Let me look at my calendar. I probably
am. I I don't know my calendar for one
one day to the next.
>> Well, you can always check the scroll
here. People here do know it. They know
more about us than we know. Maybe it's
your old colleagues in Langley. Um
tapping your phone. Yeah.
>> Uh oh, they're not supposed to do that.
Only for
>> No, they're not supposed to. But anyway,
getting back to Israel, I'm I I'm always
pessimistic when it comes to Israel and
Palestine. I'm even more pessimistic
today, Ted, than I was yesterday.
>> Um,
>> yeah, it's not good.
>> Yeah. Although, what's funny, I'm
short-term very pessimistic like you.
Long-term, I'm more pessimist. I mean,
I'm I'm more optimistic. Um, I think you
know, like we've talked about before,
the more of this [__] that Israel pulls,
the lower their approval rating goes,
the lower their support in the US goes,
the less the the more the safer it is
for American politicians to cut them off
and the more isolated they're going to
be diplomatically, including at the UN,
which the General Assembly meets here in
New York next month. Um, it's I mean I
think they're they're really cutting off
their noses despite their faces and over
and over.
>> Ted, there was a poll that was released
today. Absolutely fascinating. And you
know you you know how obsessed I am with
polls, but this was a global poll
>> and it ranked every country by how their
citizens answered if they were strongly
pro- Israel, moderately pro-Israel,
moderately anti-Israel, strongly
anti-Israel.
There were only three countries in the
world that are pro-Israel by majority
>> out of 200 or so.
>> One of one of them is Israel.
>> Okay.
>> One one of them is the United States.
>> And and the third inexplicably to me was
Nigeria.
>> Yeah.
>> What?
>> And everybody else in the world is
majority anti-Israel.
The world.
>> That's crazy. There should be
did they track how that looked compared
to previous years?
>> Yeah. And it's it's moved dramatically.
>> Dramatically. Um, interestingly, outside
the Middle East proper, to use the
British terminology, um, Turkey was the
most anti-Israel um, country in the
outside the Middle East.
>> Well, that's a dramatic change. I mean,
>> dramatic change.
>> Is that a I mean, they used to almost be
sort of allies. I mean,
>> very much so,
>> right?
>> Yes. Very much.
>> Remember during the big earthquake, uh,
they came to help out.
>> Yes. Doctors and rescue teams and
trained dogs and all that stuff.
>> Is that an Erdogan thing or what's the
story there?
>> Yeah. Erdogan has moved farther and
farther toward the religious types over
the years. And then we when he made this
decision to publicly support Hamas, that
was the end of it. And that's when the
Greeks moved in to become pro-Israel. It
was the Greeks that were always pro
Palestinian. And when the Turks
switched, the Greeks switched.
Interestingly, in Greece,
combining strongly anti-Israel and
moderately anti-Israel, in Greece, it
was 74%
that are anti-Israel, despite the fact
that the Greek government bows down
before the Israeli government.
Fascinating to me. But but but the
lesson here, at least the lesson that I
took from it,
>> is that the Israelis are dragging us
down with them.
>> You know, so many Americans believe that
if you're anti-Netanyahu, that means
you're anti-Semitic. And that you have
to be in lock step with the farthest
right-wing elements of the Israeli
government to not be anti-semitic. And
that is utter nonsense. Well, it's
insane to give any country uh who's
making their own decisions uh for their
own domestic political uh you know
reasons and to give them a blank check
and basically say whatever you guys do
in and around your neighborhood
>> we're on board with no matter what. I
mean you know it's like look it's like
if your friend is out basically we
Israel is like our really bad friend.
Yes. They're staying up late. They're
cheating on their wife. They're like
they're they're they're drinking.
They're drinking and driving. They're uh
you know trying to outrun the police and
they're calling all the time. You say
you're their one quarter. You have to go
and bail them out all the time. You're
always and and and you get blamed for
what they do. You're enabling them. It's
your car that they're doing it with. And
like I mean they're literally shooting
Palestinians with made in USA weapons.
Um yeah. I mean it literally and it's
like uh you know so when 9/11s happened
my only thing the only thing that I
found I found it shocking but I didn't
find it surprising. The only surprise is
that things like that don't happen all
the time.
>> Totally agree. Totally agree. So I hate
to say it but the bottom line for me
today is there's no reason to be
optimistic optimistic on on Palestine
today. No reason at all.
>> Let's talk about the settlements. So
yeah,
>> uh it it continues, right? Like um these
700,000
uh illegal West Bank colonists, aka
quote unquote settlers. I don't like the
word settler because it kind of implies
that nobody was living there before.
That's right.
>> Which is far from true. And um anyway,
and they're running rampant. So the um
the uh Israeli government has just
officially said they've just um green
lit this E1 settlement project um 3,400
new units. So um you know I don't know
how many average uh what's the average
family size in one of those units but
you got to figure let's say three at
least right at least.
>> So at least 10,000 more people um are
coming in there further slicing and
dicing the Palestinian communities. But
the big news here is the reason that the
Israelis are the right-wingers are so
excited about it is that this completely
severs the West Bank proper from East
Jerusalem, which was always intended to
be the capital of a new of a of a future
Palestinian state.
>> And this is basically saying, we've
completely annexed East Jer Jerusalem,
which has already happened, and you're
not even gonna we're not we're never
letting you back. That's it. You can't
even come to visit. Yeah, it it makes me
sick to my stomach. Um, and you know,
just to make matters even worse, or not
even, I won't even say it like that,
I'll say just to add insult to injury,
what the Israelis tend to do in the
weeks and months before they seize
Palestinian land is they'll go in and
bulldoze the olive orchards, for
example, or set fire to to the crops
just so it makes it easier for you to
just leave on your own. And if you don't
finally leave, they'll bulldo the house
>> and then build one of their prefab
houses and have some family from New
Jersey or New York or wherever move into
to this new house on land that's been in
in these families for hundreds of years.
>> Why do they bulldo Why do they bulldoze
the house? A lot of times these are
perfectly fine structures.
>> Yeah. In fact, in in Jerusalem, in East
Jerusalem, they they generally keep the
houses and just turn it over to a Jewish
family. But um but the um the condition
of so many of these houses in the West
Bank is so poor. They're they're thrown
together with,
>> you know, scraps and and concrete block
and whatever.
>> They're not really
they shouldn't be habitable.
>> Yeah. They're
>> But people are so desperate that this is
all they can do. They're poor. Yeah.
>> And and their their their olive trees
have been stolen or destroyed.
Yeah. Yeah. So, all right. Well, I have
to admit, um, you know, obviously, uh,
always my my loyalty here is with the
Palestinians and, uh, you know, I mean,
they will maintain the struggle. So,
that
>> Yes, they will. Hey,
>> good. And we need to thank firmware and
Houdini both. Thank you so much for your
generous contributions.
>> Oh my god, thank you so much. Yeah. Um,
like the scroll is going on here. Thank
you so much. Um,
yeah. Yeah, that's that's that's that's
crazy, right? As Houdini points out, the
olive trees are 4,000 years old. They're
some of the oldest
>> things on the on the planet.
>> Yes, they are.
>> I was uh I I was um once at a panel
discussion with other authors and there
was this woman who's was the author of a
book about the oldest things on earth.
Um and some of the oldest things on
earth are trees. There's some like shrub
>> trees. There's some shrub in Africa
that's like doesn't look like much, but
it's like six or seven thousand years
old. There's a giant sea sponge that's
thousands of years old in the Atlantic
Ocean.
>> Wow.
>> Um, and there's some giant underground
mushroom complex.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> That goes for acres and acres. It's out
in like Oregon or something.
>> Yeah.
>> There there's a there's an olive tree in
Cit 3,200 years old. It's the oldest
olive tree in in Greece. You know, when
I was living in Athens, I lived in this
normal, you know, suburban house, this
5-year-old house, but I had a a
300-year-old olive tree in my front
yard. And my first Yeah. My first year
that I was there, um, it it started
making olives and and the olives started
to ripen. So, I asked a guy at the
embassy, I said, "Hey, I have this olive
tree. It's making beautiful olives. I
don't know what to do with it." He said,
"Oh, no. We we'll take care of it. You
have a choice." He says, "We call the
olive company, the olive harvesting
company, and you can do two things. You
can either pay them to harvest the
olives,
>> or
you give them the olives to harvest
>> and they give you five gallons of the
olive oil that it creates."
>> Yeah. Because there's a lot of
processing with olives. You can't eat
them off the tree.
>> No. No. They're terrible.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So, I ended up using olive oil
from my own olives for for years. Three,
four, five years. I had that olive oil.
It was amazing.
>> That's cool. So,
>> and it's 300 years old.
>> It's 300 years old and absolutely
delicious.
>> Just think about that. Like that that
blows my mind when I think about like,
you know, what the world was like uh in
1725, right?
>> Yeah. Just in my little yard, I had a
peach tree, a plum tree, an orange tree,
a lemon tree. I had the olives and I had
a big uh tortoise.
>> Oh, really? Where's the
>> He would just eat the fruits that would
fall off the tree.
>> Oh, wow. Was he Oh, so he was like uh
wild. He was
>> Yeah, it was I I looked it up. It's
called an Addican tortoise.
>> Oh god, it sounds I would feel like a
king if I had those things. Every
morning I'd wake up and I'd feel a
little bit happy just because of that.
>> It was good. It was good. I liked it.
>> Um okay, so I think we'll leave that
there. Uh, what should we talk about?
Should we?
>> And thank you. Thank you to uh to
Matthew as well, who also has a
question. Thoughts on Trump making
cartels as terrorists. I don't think
we've really talked about that in any in
any depth. Um, when when Trump first
said that he was going to classify or
have the State Department classify the
drug cartels as terrorist groups, I said
that it was it was a bureaucratic move
because it would free up funding for the
intelligence community that otherwise is
not focused on drugs to begin things
like intercepting the communications of
of cartel uh leaders. And a lot of
people predicted that we would start
using offensive capabilities against the
cartels like drones. That hasn't
happened.
>> No.
>> Do you see any reason why
there's a benefit to to uh classifying
the cartels as terrorist groups?
>> Well, I mean, when you under American
law, right, when you classify anything
as a terrorist group, uh it opens up,
you know, you can pretty much do
anything you want. You don't need an act
you don't need an authorization from
Congress. I think it's because you can
rely on the 2001 post 911 author
authorization to use military force that
basically has never been expired, right,
as far as I know. And anything related
to terrorism in general or specifically
al Qaeda or anyone who may or may not
have been responsible for 911 or
anything like 911 blah blah blah blah,
it's so open-ended. So, um I think
that's why uh there's this this it's
very tempting for the government to just
classify anything that they don't like,
including bad weather, as a terrorist.
>> That's right. Terrorist.
>> Yeah,
>> that's exactly right.
>> Um should we talk about these t There's
We should definitely touch upon the
redistricting.
Uh oh,
>> there I am.
>> There we go. Okay. I thought it was me
again.
>> No, that was me. I uh the I have a Mac
and the iOS has sort of this quirk where
if you move the magic mouse a little too
fast, it just swipes you off.
>> Yes. Yes.
>> I hate that.
>> Mine does that, too. I also
>> I tried to see if And there's apparently
a setting that you can supposedly get
rid of that, but it doesn't work. So, we
miss you, Steve Jobs. Come back. Um, get
rid of the Apple Watch while you're at
it. Okay. So, uh, let's talk about the,
uh, redistricting thing. You wanted to
bring that up.
>> I did want to bring it up. The Texas
House is prepared now to vote in favor
of redrawing,
uh, congressional district boundaries,
which would likely result in the loss of
five Democratic House seats in Texas. Uh
Gavin Newsome has already had prepared
um a uh a comparable measure, but the
system is different in California. This
has to go to a referendum. So he would
have to call a special election.
>> Well, they're used to that in
California. They have
>> all the time.
>> They have them all the time. U the RNC,
the Republican National Committee, has
committed $15 million in advertising to
defeat it, and they've been successful
in the past.
>> Won't work this time.
Um, and so now New York, Republican,
California, California's GOP is dead.
>> It's got nothing going on.
>> Gone. Um, New York and Illinois are
jumping in saying that they're now
considering redrawing their district
boundaries. But, but Missouri and
Florida have also jumped in saying that
they're going to redraw to make it
easier for Republicans. We have never
seen anything like this in the history
of the republic. This is just such bad
form and it's such, you know,
sour grapes
and it's the worst of jerrymandering.
Now, interestingly enough, this
afternoon, a federal judge
out of thin air,
>> Thank you, Marble, by the way.
>> Thank you, Marble. A federal judge ruled
that Mississippi's district boundaries
are illegally gerrymandered.
So now Mississippi is going to be forced
to redraw its boundaries even though it
didn't want to. And it's going to have
to add a majority black district.
>> So
>> I mean gerrymandering's been with us I
mean you know
>> oh since the 18th century,
>> right? It's one of the very It may be
the first well certainly the most
well-known early American political
cartoon, right? It's the gerrymander uh
in which some district voter some ugly
looking voter district I guess in
Massachusetts I think it was um is just
basically drawn up into the into the
form of a horrible like dragon-like
monster. Yes. Um, and uh, you know, it's
so and it's I think it's Ben Franklin,
if I'm not mistaken, who created that
cartoon. Um,
>> it it it ran in Ben Franklin's paper. Do
you know the uh, do you know the
background to it? It was um, Elbridge
Garry, Ge R Y, but it was pronounced
Gary. He was the fourth vice president
of the United States.
>> Oh, wow.
>> And he had been um, the governor of
Massachusetts.
So he was, I think, Madison's vice
president. So he was intensely partisan
and in order to get his friends elected
to Congress, he just took out a map of
of Massachusetts and he drew the
district boundaries. And when Benjamin
Franklin saw them,
um, he said that they looked like
salamanders and he called them Gary's
salamanders. And that became Gary
Mander, which then over the years became
gerrymander.
He's also little little bit of trivia
from John's someday to be published
cemeteries book. He's the only vice
president of the United States to be
buried inside Washington, DC.
>> Oh, really? Where is he? Where is he
buried?
>> He's at Congressional Cemetery up on
Capitol Hill. There it is. There's the
gerrymander.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. kind of kind of a cool cartoon.
And
>> it really is. It really is.
>> Not and I doubt it's really the original
first one, but you know, uh yeah.
Anyway,
>> I like it.
>> Yeah, me too.
So, all right. So, um Yeah. So, I mean,
look, let's get to the the politics of
this. I mean, so obviously the
gerrymandering is is going to is a pace,
but it seem this to me this really uh
destroys like uh respect for the system,
right? I mean, we're just living in an
incredibly toxic time. It seems like
these two parties are far more
interested in playing these kind of sick
sorted, you know, sleazy games um behind
the scenes than representing the
interests of the American people. I
mean, there's nobody sitting around
thinking, "Okay, what's what's
afflicting most people?" There's no
Democrats or Republicans thinking, you
know, there's people who can't afford
food, everything's expensive, or you
know, kids people can't send their kids
to college even though they're really
smart,
>> or what, you know, on and on and on.
They're doing this [__] instead.
>> Yeah, you're exactly right. You're
exactly right. And I think it just
increases it furthers contempt for the
system.
>> It does. And and it it brings us back to
the comment you made at the very start
of the show about things going so badly
for the Democrats.
The Democrats are bleeding members and
money and nobody trusts them. And it's
not that the Republicans are that much
more popular. It's that the Democrats
are just so
backward.
>> Yeah. So let's be clear here because
it's a really complicated picture,
right? So first of all, Democratic voter
I'll try to pull up a chart of this, but
basically Democratic voter registration
visav Republicans is collapsing, but
overall affiliation is also declining.
So more and more Americans are ident the
biggest the fastest growing group is
really unaffiliated voters in only in 20
out of 50 states. uh you can't you you
don't register as a Democrat or
Republican or anything else. By the way,
you can register as a Green or a
Libertarian or anything you want, a
socialist, but uh 30 out of 50 states
you can or and so uh in those states
people are just like fleeing uh they're
fleeing the Democrats much faster than
they're fleeing the Republicans. John, I
have a theory about what's going on
here, which is um I think that as the
Democratic Party and the Republican
party, but the Democrats more, they've
they've they're no longer a political
movement that promotes an ideology.
They're a team.
>> And when and you ident like most of my
friends basically are parts of team
blue. They identify with the Democratic
Party because it they've always been dem
they're Democrats because they're
Democrats. the Democratic party h can
change radically in on policies like hey
let's start wars all over the place when
you know 30 40 50 years ago that's not
really who they were. Um and the
Republicans were the hawk party but
they're still Democrats. Once a Democrat
always a Democrat. Republicans also it's
a team. When you're on team red you know
you you know there's even Republican
fashions right? Like there's even like
women wear more makeup if they're
Republican. There's a way to look.
There's a car, you know, like there's a
kind of car you're more likely to buy.
So, it's this reminds me of Bzantium
where there were the the blue and the
red chariot teams. And at first, it
started out like it was just
entertainment, but over the centuries,
it evolved into political parties. There
were riots. Um, and it got to the point
where if you were from a red chariot
family or you would not let your
daughter marry a guy from a blue chariot
family. And we're seeing that, too. So,
if it's a team and not an ideology,
well, you're going to you're going to go
with the cooler team, the team that
seems to win more, that seems to have
more pizzazz. And since 2016, the team
that's had more pizzazz has been the
GOP. That's my theory.
I think you've hit it right on the head.
If I were to ask myself
who who's the leader of the Democratic
Party,
I could come up with 20 different names
or zero names.
>> Right.
By the way, Gavin Newsome, my favorite
governor, seems to be like really having
a moment these days. He he wants to be
the big uh the big kahuna and he's doing
it basically by mimicking Donald Trump
like he goes on Donald right he he's
does all cap
>> tweets and and like basically
sad exclamation point
>> tends to be Donald tries to be Donald
Trump. Um
I as a student of politics I think it's
always a mistake to be uh you know
adopting or even satarizing someone
else's framing. I think it's always
better to have your own framing and try
to make that framing better. Am I wrong?
>> No, I think you are exactly right.
>> Yes, I think you're right.
>> But it's it's like Ted, they don't they
don't have an appreciation for it. It's
like they don't see what the rest of the
country sees. When when only, you know,
24 or 25% of Americans consider
themselves to be Democrats.
>> Yeah. That's that's not a brag.
>> That's a problem.
>> That's a problem that you should be
dealing with.
>> John, you must remember in ' 04, I think
it was, two guys wrote a book called a
best-selling book called The Emerging
Democratic Majority. I remember 21 years
ago the theory was that the Republican
party was obsolete, would never win. Uh
remember when Obama was president, more
recent, right? The the the Democrats got
rid of the judicial filibuster reasoning
that the Republicans would never control
the Senate ever again,
>> ever again.
>> Never. And they said that that once
Texas turned blue, and it was turning
blue, it was imminent,
>> right?
>> That no Republican presidential
candidate would ever win again.
>> It was impossible.
>> They would have to come up with a new
party, this new political realignment.
And of course, that was all ridiculous.
>> And and obviously, yeah, it couldn't be
more different. Now, I mean, look, let
let's get into some statistics here,
right? So 4.5 million registered voter
registered voters, right? This isn't
even swing voters who are like I'm a reg
like I'm a registered Democrat in New
York, right? But I could, you know, I
could vote for a Republican if I want.
That's not even that. This is me like
calling the board of elections and
saying [__] the Democratic party. I'm
moving over to the Republicans, which
requires work, right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. You have to work at
it.
>> So So that's in just 2020 to 2024.
Now, that's a Biden effect, I think, in
in in large part. And looking back at
that, it's like, God, the way they clung
to Biden, you know, I mean, what a
catastrophe. And the other thing is they
had this assumption like voter
Democratic voter registration moves,
which are basically usually run by third
party organizations, not third parties,
but like not the Democratic party, like
labor unions and uh NOS's and so on.
They'll like go out and register people.
and they'll say, "Oh, let's just
register a bunch of black guys because
blacks always vote Democratic." And they
did,
>> right?
>> Until they didn't.
>> And and let's they always assumed
>> that all that was wrong from the outset.
>> Yeah.
>> Um and so now
>> they don't know what to do. And then the
Democrats in today's New York Times find
themselves in the awkward position of
having to confide that they're really no
longer interested in just registering
minorities. They really want to just
register Democrats and they're trying to
figure out how to do that. How can they
find their would-be Democratic voters?
>> Oh, if only there was a way to appeal to
to to the to get the Democratic party to
be more popular. I don't know, get
better candidates with good with good
issues and good publicity.
>> You would think. I I had a I had a
conversation today with a with two
Swedish professors. they have a podcast
and and we were talking exactly about
this issue and I said, you know, when
when it's the Democrats who used to be
in the streets to protest the war in
Vietnam, the Democrats who used to be in
the streets to protest the invasion of
Iraq, the Democrats that used to be
opposed to everinccreasing
uh Pentagon budgets,
who are now being endorsed by Dick
Cheney,
Right. It was Dick Cheney endorsed Kla
Harris for president. Then you know you
have a serious problem. And they
trumpeted that like it was the best
thing that had ever happened.
>> Yeah. And Dick Cheney.
>> Horrible. She went on tour with Horrible
Liz.
>> That's right. Like it was like it was a
a positive thing.
>> Like it was a get.
>> Yeah, it was. It was a get. It's nuts.
>> It's totally crazy. Yeah. I I don't know
who these people are. And then of
course, obviously, meanwhile, they had
good, reliable left-wing voters. All the
Bernie people, all would have voted
Democratic, every last one of them. But
they told all whatever seven or nine or
12 million of them, however many there
are, because it's hard to guesstimate.
There's so many, it's hard to count
them, right?
>> Um that basically we don't need you.
We're gonna we're going to find our
votes from the center. You still see
that song on the editorial pages of all
the major newspapers now. We need a good
reli sensible centrist. That's what we
need,
>> right?
>> Yeah. There's no center. You know, I
said that in this talk with the Swedes
today, too, that my very best friend
from childhood, he's a Republican, a
mega Republican, and he's always yelling
about the radical left. And I said to
him not too long ago, I said, "Gary,
what exactly is radical about the left?
You keep using that word. You every time
you talk about Democrats, you call them
the radical left. What is it that's so
radical?" And he thought about it for a
second and he said, 'Well, the Green New
Deal. I said, 'Okay, so what's so
radical about the Green New Deal? And he
didn't know because he doesn't know what
the Green New Deal is. It's just that
Fox News keeps calling it radical,
radical, radical, so it must be radical.
And now we've got this giant split down
the middle. So I said to the Swedes, I
said, "Look, we've got a right of center
party and we have a farther right of
center party." And now Elon Musk at all
want to put another right of center
party in the middle of the two right of
center parties that we already have.
That's where our politics are today.
>> Robbie's got a question too. What about
what about rank choice voting? We have
rank choice voting here in Arlington
County, Virginia, which works
beautifully. Alaska has it and it, you
know, allowed a Democrat to be elected
to one term in the House of
Representatives. But uh
>> it also gave us Eric Adams here in New
York though.
>> Well, that's true actually.
>> And every New Yorker, John, has to re
has to absorb this
>> 60page voter guide
>> which has never mind all the crazy
chart. I should I always like to keep
this as me. So, this is like this is all
it's like the SATs.
>> Yeah, you got to study it. Uh,
>> when I went to vote, I I screwed up.
Now, granted, I only went to an Ivy
League school, so I'm not that smart,
but I screwed up. And I went over and I
said, "I'm really sorry. I screwed it
up." And the lady had a giant bin of of
of spoiled ballots,
>> you know, and I live in a neighborhood
next to, you know, a major university.
>> Yeah.
>> One that's been in the news for being
anti-Semitic,
>> right?
>> Yeah. So,
>> Oh, good grief.
It's it's nuts. Yeah. No, rank choice I
don't think rank I look I think rank
choice vote voting works when it votes
works and it doesn't work when it
doesn't work you know I mean
>> I think you know I think it in certain
particular circumstances like it would
really the Bernie bros loved it because
they were like there were so many people
who were like well I really want to vote
for Hillary more but I still like Bernie
and I would vote him for him second.
It's kind of like a John Hughes movie
where it's like that, you know, Molly
Ringwald likes John, but she would also
date Ted if John were like not around
and maybe if Ted had a better car.
>> And so that's like so that's what rank
choice voting is like. And uh but and I
but I don't think that plays out really
in a lot of cases. I think people in
most cases are like
>> you're lucky if they like even one
candidate.
Uh the Gracemeister
uh is asking when was the last
Democratic presidential primary open
presidential primary. I mean technically
I guess it was 20 uh uh 20 but not
really because the fix was in for Biden.
It would have been 2008, but even that
was supposed to be the Hillary
coronation and it came down to just
Hillary and uh and uh Obama. So when was
the last time that it was truly open? It
has to be like 92, right?
>> Well, 92. Yeah. The fix was still in to
some extent, right? I mean, it's Yeah.
And I was there um in the convention
hall when that happened. Um I'm trying
to think like when it was really thrown
open. I don't know, John. I'd have to go
back to 1980. I'd have to say um
>> for the Democrats when Ted
>> challenged Jimmy Carter
>> even though also I was in the hall for
that and let me I was a young man I was
17 and let me just say the party they
pulled they went full spectrum DNC in
1980 they changed the rules
>> so that uh so that Carter would get the
nomination. I'm convinced that Ted
Kennedy would have had a better shot
against Reagan in terms of uh you know,
a more enthusiastic liberal base. Um,
you know, we really we lost out when we
didn't get Ted Ted Kennedy uh to you
know, possibly be the president of the
United States with all of his flaws.
Don't let him drive your daughter home.
But
>> yeah, don't let him drive your daughter
home. Yeah, ask Mary Joe Capeknney about
that. Well, you can't.
But yeah, I agree. I agree.
>> Should we talk about Ted?
>> Go ahead,
>> Ted. Sorry, one one more question. We're
three and a half years out from or three
years plus a couple of months out from
the next uh election, but we're only
really a year and a half out from the
start of the primary.
>> Yes.
>> So, I is a year and a half enough time
for the Democrats to get their act
together?
>> No [__] way. I mean, not to mention,
look, you remember the last person who
really nationalized a midterm election
was N. Gingrich in 1994 with the
>> contract with America.
>> Brilliant um brilliant politics, not
really brilliant policy.
>> And um you know, I mean, I think you
need a figure like that who can unify
the de Democratic party. John, do you
see a Keem Jeff doing that?
>> Not a chance. I'll tell you what, every
time I see a Jeff his ass in the
morning.
>> No. Every time I see him on TV,
I like him less. To the point now I
don't even want to hear his voice. What
a tool. He's a tool of the of the
Hillary Clinton
element of the DNC.
>> Yeah.
>> There's nothing progressive about this
guy at all. Nothing.
>> No. And he's and he's impotent.
>> I mean, you know, hand you know, Nancy
Pelosi for all of her numerous flaws.
Well, except she's a really cany
investor also. Um, you know, aside from
for but she at least, you know, she was
a strong woman. Mama be there. Yeah. She
ran she ran a tight ship.
>> Yeah. Yes, indeed.
>> So, yeah. No, I don't think the No, I
mean, look, I think the Democrats are
going to Here's the thing. The wild card
is these redistricting battles, but
there's a lot more pickups possible for
the Republicans than there are for the
Democrats. Yes. I I have to say I don't
see a road to victory next year for the
Democrats. I don't see I don't see where
it comes from. I mean, even if there's a
tremendous scandal in the GOP, even if
Trump imploded somehow, and I don't
think that's going to happen, then I
still don't see how the Democrats can
take advantage. I mean, I think their
best shot is in 2028 to nominate someone
spectacular as president and hope that
they hope that he had he or she has
coattails. And I don't think they'll
have coattails because Democrats don't
have a farm system. Obama got rid of the
farm system
>> such as it was. And I mean, I think the
Democratic part is in real trouble. I
mean, you know, we don't want to write
them off completely like the GOP was
written off completely. Obviously, um
GOP was written off completely in 1964.
>> Boy, was it.
>> And but
>> 19 1974
>> in a two-party system, one party can
always come back, but it's like but I
don't think I don't see it happening
anytime soon.
>> No,
>> totally agree. Totally agree.
>> So, speaking of elections, um I love I
love love love this story about Janine
Piro and Fox News. So, basically,
Smartmatic
uh sued Fox News three four years ago
for $2.7 billion dollars for defaming
their voting machines for saying that
they were used by the Democrats to throw
the election to Trump. Janine Beriro,
who is now the attorney general of the
District of Columbia.
>> No, she's the US attorney,
>> US attorney for District Columbia and
and not defending the people of the
district from the military invasion. No,
she's defending the cops from
sandwiches,
>> right? So, but it's not just her. Um,
there apparently there were all these
internal deliberations and basically
she's quoted in saying things about how
uh she so she so for example uh here's a
quote here's one of my favorite quotes.
Um Janine Janine goes I work so hard for
the president and the body and and the
party. Uh, she said she uh she only
cared about one thing, which was getting
a pardon for her ex-husband. I don't
even know what he did. Um, do you know?
>> No idea. But I asked her to help me and
I talked to her assistant and she says,
"20,000."
And I said, "Come on, man. I don't have
20,000. I'm just asking for a tweet.
Just just a tweet. Pardon Kuryaku.
20,000." I said, "Forget it."
>> Wow. The only interaction I've h I've
had with her, I was on the show once
and 20,000. I said, "Forget it." And she
never invited me back.
>> Do you think Do you think it would have
worked?
>> No.
>> So, there's that, too.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh such high prices, such low, such
small servings. Um
>> awful people.
>> So, I guess so also among the other
stuff that came out is a lot of
squabbbling inside in F Fox. It's all
from the discovery process, right? When
you sue someone, you can get all their
internal communications and read all
that stuff. Um, so anyway, some of this
is really juicy, right? So here's Jesse
Waters, who's on, you're probably
familiar if you watch the five as I do
every day or I did every day until we
got this show. Um, he was talking to
Greg Gutfeld. Uh, think about all the
incred how incredible our ratings would
be in 2020 if Fox went allin on Stop the
Steel, which was of course Trump's
attempt to overthrow to overturn the
election uh or to just sort of deny that
that there was any way that Biden could
legitimately win. Um, and and basically
there's a lot of behindthe-scenes stuff
about how much Sean Hannity is a mad
egotist, which really comes as no
surprise to anyone.
>> There's a shock.
>> Apparently, this is my favorite moment.
He walked into the Oval Office, you
know, where the presidents of the United
States, the leader of the free world,
the commander and chief of the armed
forces is hanging out, throws his [__]
his files or paperwork, whatever, on the
uh Resolute desk and just basically says
announces, "I got to take a piss and
goes and use the private ba the
president's private bathroom without
asking permission." Like, it's his
joint. And basically, he's just swinging
his dick around, literally.
>> Oh my god. Oh my god. I don't even know
what to say to that.
>> I mean, it's just it's such a I mean,
honestly, that TV show Succession, it
turns out that that that's a
documentary.
>> And you know, in all seriousness, that's
why they took VEP off the air because
all that crazy [__] that happened in VEP
actually started happening in real life
in the Trump administration.
They canceled the show.
>> Totally insane. So, yeah. So, I don't
know.
It's just worth knowing. I mean,
>> John, do you think the Oh, oh, by the
way, I should say that Fox was really
pissed that this all came out and that
they're getting their asses kicked in
all of these defamation cases. They
claim that they're using their god-given
first amendment right
>> to express their free speech and that
they're being censored by the man for uh
by these defamation claims. The only
thing that pisses me off about these
defamation claims is that apparently you
have to be a giant multinational
corporation in order to be able to take
on a cable news station like Fox News,
which, you know, slimes people every
single day, but they can't do anything
about it.
>> Yes. I'm going to add something, too.
Yesterday, I got a letter uh not a
welcome letter. Uh oh.
>> Saying that um that I'm going to be
called as a witness in um in a uh
defamation case against Rudy Giuliani.
>> Oh boy.
>> Yeah. Because that son of a [__] tried
to squeeze $2 million out of me for a
pardon back when five and a half years
ago.
And the story just keeps bubbling along
and bubbling along. Who's the plaintiff,
if I may?
>> It's It's Noel Duny. She used to be his
assistant and his her he she was his
director of business development at
Giuliani Partners. Um, apparently the
day that the New York Times story came
out where I was quoted as saying that he
tried to squeeze me for 2 million, um,
he said to her that son of a [__]
Kiryaku ratted me out to the New York
Times. That's what she's alleging in the
lawsuit. He then called the New York
Times and said that he and I had never
met. He didn't know who I was, the
meeting never took place, and that I had
made the whole thing up. So, I told the
reporter from the Times, I said, "That
idiot forgot that we took a picture
together."
>> OMG.
>> Uhhuh. So, I sent the I sent the picture
to the selfies.
>> I sent the picture to the Times and the
Times said Giuliani denied denied
denied. The Times has seen documentary
proof that the meeting took place.
>> John, um, what is her claim exactly? Why
is she suing Giuliani?
>> Her claim is that he never paid her over
the course of a year and a half. It was
just promises, promises, promises. And
then he sexually assaulted her twice by
forcing her forcing her to perform
sexual acts on him in exchange for him
not ruining her reputation in the
Republican party.
>> But this is a defamation claim. Where's
the defamation piece?
>> He ended up ruining her reputation in
the Republican party.
>> Yeah. So she's suing him for millions of
dollars. Isn't he broke though?
>> He says he is. Her her attorneys are
arguing that he has more than $100
million hidden in overseas accounts.
>> Good luck getting him.
>> Yeah,
>> if that's true,
>> it's cuz I don't have enough problems in
my life. I'm going to get involved in
Rudy Giuliani's uh [__]
>> Well, you'll just have to give a
defamation. I mean a uh not What am I
What am I saying? A deposition.
>> Deposition. I'll do a deposition and be
done with it.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, I mean that's no fun.
>> And just all you do is you just tell the
truth.
>> That's it.
>> Just tell the truth. That's it.
>> Yeah. I mean,
>> and then you get up and leave.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And And you know Yeah. I
mean, I've I've done this. It's as you
know, you've done this.
>> Um Yeah. It's it's nothing to nothing to
fear here. Um
>> Yeah.
>> Awful.
>> Oh, okay. So, here Oh, Robbie, thank you
so much for this. Yeah, Albert Albert
Piro was arrested and convicted in 2000
on 34 chances accounts of conspiracy and
tax evasion. He had improperly deducted
over a million bucks in personal
expenses for his lavish lifestyle as a
business writeoff for his real estate
business. He served 17 months in prison.
He got disbarred, although his law
license got reinstated in ' 07. In
January of 21, as one of his last acts,
Trump did pardon Albert Piro, uh the
arrest and conviction were s were
significant. I don't know what the count
whatever. I don't know what the rest of
that is. Okay. But anyway, that's good
to know. I I'm
>> 34 counts. 34 felony counts of
conspiracy intent.
>> You know, those You know, those counts
can add up.
>> Yeah, they do.
>> Um you know, they I always assume that
everyone's overcharged. Um
So um okay so we can I do want I really
want to well I want to talk about
everything here. Uh let's talk about the
main topic that we had here. Um so AI is
has been used all these AI chat models
uh like chat GPT these large language
models um and Grock uh which is uh X
Elon Musk's company and there's Google
AI they've all been scraping
intellectual property from all over the
internet in order to quote unquote train
themselves. So if you're if you go do a
search on Google about anything like for
example uh you know tell me about the
status of uh Israel's invasion of Gaza
you'll get search results like in the
old days to links but you're on top
you'll see Google AI and uh it will
summarize the current sit the answer to
your question whatever it is and it
might may or may not have two tiny one
or two tiny little links that blink and
you miss it, a little icon. Most people
never do. Um, and so what's going on is
that um it's called AI interview uh
overview, right? Um news websites are
say are saying that they're seeing their
web traffic has declined by as much as
50%. Ever since Google AI overview was
inter was uh in was introduced now.
>> Wow. Basically, it's not news that like
basically print newspapers are where 99
well 90% plus of all news reporting
comes from, right? If it's on the radio,
if it's on TV, it's on the internet, it
came out of a print newspaper. And those
papers have been in trouble since 1960.
>> That's 1960 is when newspaper
circulation peaked out. Then TV started
eroding at it. Um, then in the 90s, the
internet came into play. uh information
wants to be free. They gave away a lot
of their [__] Craigslist ate up all the
classified ads. The internet ate up all
of the display ads. And it's just been
death by a million very large gashes
really. And so this, you know, now
you're looking at a situation where like
the LA Times may very well be out of
business by the end of next year. Fourth
largest.
>> It kind of looks like that. Yeah. So,
you know, we're we're we're looking at
we already have major news deserts in
smaller towns. Um Canton, Ohio lost its
newspaper a couple of years ago. Um and
it's going to happen more and more. So,
there's whole sections of the country
that have no local reporting. It's a
golden age for political corruption. Um
and so, uh basically there's the the
publishers are fighting back a little
bit. They're they're they're suing uh
these big tech companies, but they're
[__] right? I mean, it's too late.
It's too little too late, isn't it?
>> Yeah, it seems that way. Even my own
little local newspaper, the Newcastle
News, which I I try to scan every day,
became so expensive, you know, I spend
what, like 50 bucks a year on the Post,
60 bucks a year on the Times, whatever
it is, just to have access. But the
little Newcastle news that does not have
a Wednesday edition or a Sunday edition
is $250 a year. I can't afford $250 a
year for a, you know, a 16page
uh local newspaper. And as a result,
they can't afford to hire journalists.
The editor is like 28 years old. They
they cover the local, you know, county
fair and the farm show and and who grew
the biggest pumpkin and what the local
churches are up to. But you're right,
it's a news desert. There's no there's
no other way to describe it. I suppose,
you know, you can if you want regional
news, you can subscribe to one of the
Pittsburgh papers, but even the
Youngsttown Vindicator, and Youngsttown
was a big city. it at 110 120,000 people
and it's it's done. Its papers done. The
Youngsttown vindicator.
>> I I mean I have to say I really don't
understand why. I mean I would like to
the the remedy here is civil court,
right? But it seems to me like this is
something Congress if it had any sense
of responsibility whatsoever would take
a look at in trying to trying to protect
news gathering. I mean it benefits polit
I know they don't like journalists
because journalists can expose their
skull dugy but I mean it's but don't but
it's kind of still to their advantage
because they need the media to publicize
their campaigns and their messages. It's
how they they get free advertising in
between elections. Um, you would think
that they would just have an interest in
propping up these news organizations and
passing a law that a basic I mean what's
needed here is a revenue sharing model,
right? Like if you if you scrape my
content from my paper that I own, you
have to pay me.
>> Yes. Yes. There's got to be, you know, I
remember back in 2000 when when the
internet was just starting to get a real
foothold. It had been around six, seven,
eight years, whatever it was. And I
remember my my start screen being
Washingtonpost.com.
And I remember thinking again 25 years
ago, how are they going to make money if
I can read the entire newspaper for free
online?
Why would I buy it? That doesn't make
any sense. And the the hard copy paper,
of course, you know, on Sundays there'd
be a hundred pages of ads. You're not
getting that online.
>> Yeah. I don't know that I don't know
that like the newspaper uh Barons ever
gave any thought really to the way
people actually consume their product.
Um you know uh when this all went
started in the mid to late 1990s uh my
thought was what really makes sense. I
mean I I I still was reading a print
paper and reading online. Now to this
day I'm a subscri I'm a digital
subscriber to the New York Times and the
Washington Post. If I subscribe to the
print edition or if I pick up the print
edition, most of what's in there I read
yesterday online already.
>> Yep.
>> Now, that that product costs more. Yes.
>> Than the product that I'm paying for.
>> This should be exactly the way other way
around. I think the internet should be
for breaking news that tells you it
should tell you what just happened. You
know, Israel just invaded Kunis and Gaza
City. Tomorrow in the print edition,
there should be big deep dive analysis
pieces that explain
>> what happened la, you know, yesterday
and what's likely to happen in in like
the days ahead. Sort of like analogous
to the way that the news weeklys that
role that Time Newsweek, US News and
World Report used to play.
>> That's right. That's exactly right.
>> But nobody listens to Ted R.
>> No. Or John Kuryaku.
But, you know, at least we're cute. Um,
all right. So,
JRock want to know, why is Jake Tapper
so miserable?
>> I don't know. If I was making what Jake
Taber makes, I'd be pretty darn happy
all the time.
>> Yeah, I know. That's how I feel about
it, too. Heaven knows I'm miserable now,
as the as the Smiths once saying. Um,
you know, I ran into a friend of mine, a
fellow cartoonist with whom I'm often
confused at a bar the other day and uh
he was he was saying like, "Ah, I'm
depressed." I'm like, "You love it. You
love to make yourself miserable." He
goes, "Fuck you." And then he started
laughing because he's like, "You're
right." Uh Jake strikes me as he might
be that person, but I'm not going to
psychoanalyze a guy who um you know,
who's not here. Um
anyway, uh a this is great. Peter Ivy
says, "We're listening to Ted Roll and
John Kiryaku." That's right.
>> So you're happy. You're happy.
>> Um anyway, yeah, here we go. This Ted,
that was the uh Cobalt Chimera says,
"Ted, that was the whole fight for ages.
Advertising, referral links, summaries,
substitute for original product in
copyright." Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, it was.
Yeah, that's right.
Um,
so, um, Oh, yeah, you know, this has
come up and I guess we probably should.
Where is this question? Uh, everything
is going by so fast here. Someone asked
about the is do we want to talk about
the Israeli pedophile thing again or
not? We kind of already talked about it.
>> You know, the only thing that's new is
is the um the Justice Department said
that they played no role in this at all.
Nothing at all. I find that very hard to
believe because because we're talking
about electronic images
uh and we're talking about electronic
communications to try to meet up with a
with an underage girl. That would make
it federal.
So
what? The Justice Department just told
the local authorities in Las Vegas to
handle it and they let the guy go and he
just ran back to Israel. I don't know.
Somebody's lying.
>> Yeah. Yeah. agreed. Um, Russia and
Ukraine basically uh Trump wants it's
not a formal deadline, but Trump would
like uh Putin to meet with uh Zalinski
by Friday.
>> By Friday.
>> And uh and I I assume Trump will be
there, too, although he's not formally
committing to that yet. What do you
think? I mean, right now it's I think
the silence is the negotiations to try
to make that happen. Yeah,
>> I would I would hope that that's the
case. Um, the international media seem
to believe that um that the Russians
aren't interested in meeting with
Silinski, at least not on Friday.
>> But I think
>> Why wouldn't they? Why wouldn't they be?
>> Because they're winning.
>> But they're not winning at fast speed,
right?
>> No. No. But there has to be something in
it for them more than than what they're
apparently being offered,
>> right?
>> I mean, I hope they do. I I'd love to
see this thing come to an end ASAP.
Like I've said a thousand times, if
we're going to be, you know, peace
activists or supporters of peace, then
by God, let's be supporters of peace, uh
rather than to to watch all this
posturing. But um I don't know. I'm just
not seeing
a rush to the negotiating table.
>> Last but not least, I believe this will
be last Oklahoma.
Um, PRA has is has adopted a new teacher
screening test that requires uh
applicants from blue states like New
York and California to get a perfect
score on a 50 question exam in order to
weed out quote unquote woke people.
You know what's funny too is that states
like Oklahoma and Kansas are having
serious problems attracting teachers.
>> And in fact, in fact, in places like
Kansas City, Kansas,
those teachers are resigning and moving
to Missouri, right? Where they don't
have to put up with silliness like this.
Same thing in Oklahoma. They're just
moving to Texas, moving to other states
where they're treated like human beings.
They don't have to go through this
political indoctrination.
So, here's some questions from that from
that test. Number one, what are the
first three words of the Constitution?
A, in God we trust. B, life, liberty,
and happiness. C, the United States. D,
we the people.
I mean, I know the answers to that.
>> Yeah, me too. All right.
>> If you're a teacher and you don't know
the answer, then share. Why is freedom
of religion important to America's
identity? A, it makes Christianity the
national religion. B, it bans all form
of public worship. C, it limits
religious teaching in public life. D, it
protects religious choice from
government control.
Number three. Oh, here this is I'll just
do one more. Number five. Why do some
states have more representatives than
others?
>> A, they cover a larger geographic area.
B. They have held statehood for a longer
period. C. The number is determined by
military presence. D. Representative
representation is determined by
population size. I mean, you'd have to
be really a [__] to not be able.
>> Yeah, very much so. Although, you know
what? When I was serving in Bahrain, we
had a uh we had a secretary in the
political section who thought that the
State Department was a division of the
Pentagon.
Oh my.
>> Yeah, there are a lot of lot of dum dums
out there.
>> Yeah. Yeah, there are. Um,
yeah, this is funny. Uh, Houdini says,
"I lived in Oklahoma. They need all the
teachers they can get."
>> Hilarious. And Nick Otto says, "The top
superintendent of all Oklahoma public
schools currently embroiled in a porn
scandal on his TV in the office. The
porn was allegedly se by seen by
students. Lovely people all around. OMG.
And then we'll last and we'll leave it
there. DNI Tulsi Gabbard announced
overhaul of the department of her
department cutting over 40% of staff.
>> I mentioned today in in a podcast that
when the ODNI, the office of the
director of national intelligence was
first created, it had 16 employees. Now
it has 20,000 employees. So yeah, they
need to cut staff.
>> So the idea for DNI was post 911, right?
To put to have more coordination behind
between all the agencies,
>> especially as it related to the budget.
Yes.
>> Well, bureaucracy grows and grows and
grows. Um, all right. Good.
>> Thanks everyone for joining us. Uh,
appreciate it. You're here Monday
through Friday, 5:00 p. a.m., which
means we will be back tomorrow,
Thursday, at 5:00 p. p.m. Eastern time.
No idea what we'll have to talk about,
but we will talk about something.
>> Ted, do we have any ads before we leave?
>> Oh, good, good, good question. Let's
take a look at the Rumble feed here.
Looks like uh No, we don't.
>> Okay.
>> Oh, actually, maybe we do. Um, you know,
okay. Honestly, I have to admit I'm a
little greedy. It tells you how much you
get and and the money is so little. I'm
gonna let you go.
>> Like two and a half bucks. Yeah.
>> Not even.
>> Yeah. I'm like, you know what's the word
I'm looking for? [__] that. Yeah.
>> So,
>> okay. Well, I'm deprogrammed.
>> I am I am completely deprogrammed. Uh we
will I'll figure out how to take that
that uh DNI comment offline somehow.
Anyway, thanks everybody and uh talk to
you later. See you tomorrow. Oh, please
like, follow, and share the show. Just a
reminder, if you're not watching this on
Rumble, please do um if you become
Rumble Premium, you can watch us for
five bucks or you can watch everything
on Rumble for 10 bucks a month. And we
get paid a lot lot lot lot more. Believe
me, John and I are looking at these
numbers every single day to see if we're
going to be able to make our rent. So,
um it's and so far we can't. So, uh the
things are moving in the right
direction. Thank you so much for that.
Thanks for all the generous financial
contributions as well. And so anyway,
take care and see you tomorrow night.
>> Thanks everybody.